[music]
>> 2026 has been wild.
I've lost a lot.
I've made a lot.
>> [music]
>> And I've learned a lot.
Let's get right into it, so you know
what I'm talking [music] about.
2026 has been a crazy year. And give me
20 to 30 minutes, and I'm going to
change your trading entirely with just
this video alone.
About 12 months ago, I had one of the
scariest moments in my professional
career happen to me when I crashed this
car. I crashed a $5 million hypercar at
3:00 in the morning.
Extremely scary moment. Not only being
in the accident, but knowing all the
repercussions that would happen after
that. Am I going to lose my dream car
that I worked so hard for? Am I going to
lose the $5 million that I paid? Did I
hurt somebody? Am I going to get sued?
Can I even fix the car? There were so
many things happening at that very
moment that felt like there was never
going to be a solution. I felt like I
had my life ended at that point.
And you fast forward 12 months, and I've
managed to turn the biggest negative
that happened at that very moment into a
massive positive, While having
billion-dollar companies go against us
and not believing us, while having the
brand not support us and us finding
solutions to it,
>> [music]
>> it's because we're resilient. We're not
going to let a negative take us down. We
will flip that turn that into a
positive. We turn a scary scenario into
the best outcome possible. And that's
what trading is right now in 2026. I get
it at first glance, as soon as you get
started, you might be confused. Why
don't I get this? Why am I losing? I
might feel scary. And then you fast
forward 2-3 months in your journey and
things start to make sense and you turn
a negative into a positive if you know
what you're doing. But a lot of people
don't know what they're doing. Like how
I didn't know what I was doing when I
was building this car. So I partnered up
with the right person, Matt Armstrong,
and he's been an amazing person to build
this car and has made this journey
seamless. Trading is no different. If
you start off in the wrong foot, it can
be very difficult for you to actually
have success and see [music] some type
of results in it. So this video is that
change in your journey. Give me 20 to 30
minutes and everything is going to
change for you. So let's get right into
it. So the start of 2026 was already
random. Presidents getting abducted. Who
knew that that was going to happen,
right? And lucky enough for me or
unlucky enough for me, I was stuck in an
island. I was stuck in Saint Bart's for
the entirety of the beginning of the
year where there was a no-fly zone
restriction, so I wasn't able to leave
the island back to the states and I was
having to be stuck there. Not a bad
place to be stuck. But that just shows
the volatility on how 2026 was going to
go. Trump is not effing around. He's
going to be very aggressive as to what
he's going to do in his term and that
directly affects [music] the markets.
Now, many traders that have never traded
in these type of markets before don't
know how to adapt to it, especially if
they're coming from least volatile
markets. When I got involved in trading
in [music] 2019, I I already trading in
these aggressive markets, traded in the
Biden markets where things were very
predictable because not much was going
on fundamentally, [music]
and now they became very volatile again.
Now, this volatility is good if you
understand [music] what you're doing.
And for me personally, I've been a
successful trader for about 5 years.
I've been trading for about 7 years.
And
even me knowing what I'm doing, I
entered a massive losing streak at the
beginning of the year. My first 2 months
of 2026 were losing trade after trade
after trade. Now, that's already as
embarrassing as it is
because I'm putting all this out there.
I'm putting out there that I'm a
successful trader, but I'm losing in
front of everybody every single week,
every single time I click the buy or the
sell button. And that's fine. I'm not
going to let a losing streak change my
strategy, not going to let it change my
mindset, not going to let it change my
plan. If my plan has been working for
the last 5 years successfully, this
massive shift in the market is happening
with reason because there's new
volatility coming into the market. So,
you have to expect for the market to
react some type of way. A president has
never been abducted before. What do you
expect for the market to react normal?
No, it's going to have a major reaction,
especially when they're so heavily being
influenced by the price of oil and by
all these different commodities, [music]
which is the interest of Trump.
So, this losing streak at the beginning
of the year was very challenging for me
because if it was just a personal losing
streak and it's not [music] being
publicly put out there, it'd be fine.
But, the public pressure, the students
in my community even having some doubts
at the time if their own mentor is
losing, how are they going to win? And
this just
builds character, same exact way how
crashing this car and having to face
CEOs that aren't supportive of you. This
builds resilience because if you're able
to push through such a negative moment,
you will come out on the other side. And
what it does is it makes you stick to a
plan. If you're going to adjust your
strategy just because you're having
moves that are happening random in the
market, that means you never had a plan
in the first place. I know the exact
approach that I am looking for when I go
to the market, and if I don't get that
approach, I will not enter the trade.
I'm not going to go look for a new
opportunity because the type of
opportunity that I'm interested in is
not presenting itself. That's not how
trading works when you're a successful
trader. Now, this losing streak lasted
about 2 and 1/2 months, and I'm talking
about not losing one trade and winning
another trade. No, I'm talking about
losing trade after trade after trade. I
think I lost 12 trades in a row. Now,
for someone that doesn't have a proper
strategy and someone that doesn't have
risk management, this would have
completely wiped them out entirely.
Probably make them even quit or take a
break from trading. That's what a lot of
traders do when they have a massive
losing streak like this. For me, this
didn't affect my lifestyle. This didn't
affect my mindset. This didn't affect my
plan, my account. This didn't affect
anything. Sure, I took a little hit on
my account, which is very fine, but it
didn't change anything with the way how
I am personally as a trader. Because
right after that losing streak, I
entered a 3-week winning streak where I
made back all those losses and stayed in
profit. Think about that for a second. 2
and 1/2 months of losing and 3 weeks
makes all that back and more. That is
because I have a profitable strategy and
I have a profitable plan. Because I
stuck to my plan. If I'm looking for a
break and retest for an entry on a pro
trend continuation trade, if I'm buying
at a weekly area of interest and I'm
waiting for a daily rejection, and if in
the last 2 months that has been going to
stop loss, I am not going to just change
that plan. If for the last 5 years that
has been working, I'm going to stick to
that. So, even though in those first 2
months of the year, I was looking for
those break and retest [music] from the
weekly highs, retesting an area of
interest with a daily rejection, and it
was going straight to stop loss. I said,
"Hey, this is fine. This is part of
trading. This is a losing streak. It is
totally normal."
I did not avoid that specific pattern
because I lost for 2 and 1/2 months. Not
at all. If anything, I continuously
waited for that pattern because I know
based off of probabilities, I'm going to
win the next trade. And because I have a
positive risk reward, I will be
profitable. It's just math. Let's say
out of 10 trades, I lose five, that's
minus five points, and I win five at a
1:2.
That's 10. So, I'll make back the five
that I lost, and I'll stay with an extra
five. That's exactly what I did for the
first quarter of the year. Lost for 2
months, 3 weeks made it back because I
stuck to the plan. I waited for the
exact same pattern time and time again.
I did not care if I just lost 12 trades
in a row looking for that specific
pattern. That was just the probability
of that specific setup. I missed out on
major other opportunities because I was
falling asleep in London session, didn't
wake up early enough in New York
session, and it's fine. That is my
personal problem as a human because
there is a human input when you trade at
scale, and I'm not going to blame that
on the strategy or go look for a
different opportunity. I'm just going to
wait for the opportunity to come to me,
and when it presents itself and it makes
sense, I take the trade, and I don't
think about it. When I entered this
3-week winning streak,
I didn't look to triple down my risk so
I make back those losses plus more in a
very aggressive amount of time. Not at
all. I know I'm going to enter a winning
streak because I'm sticking to my plan.
Now, sadly, which not really sadly, just
the reality, that winning streak came to
an end. I was winning for 3 weeks
entirely, entered one position, got
wicked out by 40-50 pips, and then it
went straight to my take profit. How do
you think I felt?
Nothing. If I managed to lose for 2 and
1/2 months entirely, you think I'm going
to let one trade that lost
and it took my winning streak completely
affect my trading? Not at all. All I
simply do is wait for the next
opportunity that got me back in that
winning streak, which I entered in the
losing streak, but just happened to
enter me into a winning streak, and wait
for it again. It is really that simple,
and just traders don't have the mindset
to fight in that meantime. I get it,
it's hard. You have to go to school, you
have to go to work, you have your
girlfriend, your boyfriend, your mom,
your dad, your sister, your siblings,
school, boss, whatever the case is.
All that you need to leave it at the
door. Leave it outside.
That cannot come into your space of
trading because that has no association
to what EUR/USD is going to do. Has no
association to what gold is going to do.
Gold is going to do whatever it's going
to do, if your girlfriend loves you, if
she hates you, if your dog died, if your
dog is with you, if your if this doesn't
matter. Whatever's going to be happening
from the markets, it's going to be that
regardless of what's happening outside.
So, you need to trade for what the
markets are in front of you, not for
what's happening outside of your life.
And I don't know why it causes a lot of
traders curiosity as to how I
specifically got out of a losing streak,
or how can you avoid a losing streak?
There's nothing that you can do right
now to avoid a losing streak. There's
nothing. [music]
There's no tool, there's no course,
there's no mentor, there's no strategy,
there's no entry signal, there's no
pair, there's no market, there's no
session. There is nothing that you can
do to avoid a losing streak, and I'm
just going to say that right now.
Whoever tells you that they can help you
avoid a losing streak is lying to your
face. Whenever you go enter a trade in
the market, there is a uncertain
outcome. If there is a uncertain
outcome, there is a gamble associated
with that risk that you're taking. If
you are risking something with no
guarantee, it's technically a gamble.
So, that gamble is minimized by the
amount of probabilities that you have in
order to go in one direction or the
other. There's no amount of
probabilities that you can have for it
to be 100% guaranteed going in one
direction. Does not matter. And the best
analogy that I've always put to an
example like this is like let's say
right now I am a baseball player. And my
job as a baseball player is to swing at
the best pitch that I am getting.
There's a machine pitching me a ball
endlessly throughout the day. Does not
get tired. I don't have any other
teammates. There's no crowd. There's no
clock. There's no goal. The only goal is
for me to swing at the right pitch. And
I have endless amounts of pitches. I am
not forced to swing by any means. My job
is to stand there at home base and just
wait for that perfect ball. Whatever I
consider to be the perfect ball for me
to take the risk and swing.
Now,
every single ball that is pitched down
the line has no association to the last
ball. One ball could be a fastball. One
ball could be a curveball. One ball
could be a knuckleball.
There's no pattern as to what the next
ball could be. So, if I were to swing at
a fastball
and miss,
does that mean that the next
pitch that I'm going to get will be a
fastball and I will miss? Probably not.
Because it might be a fastball again and
then if I learn from my mistake as to
what I did previously, I can probably
hit it. If the next ball comes as a
knuckleball and I don't like
knuckleballs, I'll wait for the fastball
because I made a mistake on the fastball
and I learned from that mistake and I
know where to implement it. That's
exactly what trading is. There's
hundreds of opportunities being thrown
at you every single day.
And you are by no means forced to enter
one of those positions. Not even one of
them. You only enter the position if it
makes sense. You should look for a
specific approach that comes every
single time. Whether that's a fastball,
a curveball, whatever it is that you
like, whatever your strategy is,
whatever you feel okay with risking.
Now, if you were to swing and you were
to miss, you're not going to just give
up and just swing at the next one like a
maniac because you're mad that you
missed at the last one. That's how you
lose, that's how you get emotional, and
that's how you get kicked out of the
game.
Now, [snorts] with trading is the exact
same thing. You look for a specific
entry in the market that makes the most
sense to you, and you swing at it, or
you take that trade, whenever the
opportunity is good. If you were to lose
that position, don't go and find a
different opportunity that makes you
believe that the next one won't lose. If
you know something works and it's
totally fine if you lose, stick to that.
That's what I did to get out of my
losing streak. I have my specific ball
that I like to wait for, and if I miss
at it 15, 20 times, it's fine. I know
when the perfect one comes and I'll
swing at it correctly, I'll get that
home run. That's me sticking to my plan
and not deviating it just because I feel
some type of way that I'm not winning in
that very moment. Trading is a marathon,
not a sprint. Now, I want you to write
this down.
You don't need to take every single
trade setup. You don't need to swing at
every ball.
Wait for the right one.
That's it. That right there, by itself,
will make you avoid losses, will make
you stick to a specific setup that you
like and that it makes sense for you and
you know that it works, and you will
stay consistent to your plan. The plan
is by far the most [music] important
thing. Now, you not taking every
opportunity that the market gives you is
already good because you're playing
defense with all of the unnecessary
trades that you have to take. But, there
will be a moment where you have to take
a trade and there will be risk involved.
[music] Whether you're going to risk a
dollar to make two dollars, there's
always a risk associated to make
something. You need to risk something in
order to gain something. That's just how
life works. That [music] is trading that
that principle in trading plus to life
as a whole. For example, right now I'm
taking a big risk, a very big risk. I'm
building right now my trading floor. As
you guys know, this trading floor is a
massive investment, massive operation,
takes away from what I'm currently doing
in my personal life, and I'm risking all
that time that I invest into building
this if people don't like it or nobody
ends up showing up. I'm taking a big
financial risk. I'm already in a way
over budget for what I have currently
done. I'm already in about $430,000.
And it almost feels like I've done
nothing. I've only done some concrete
slabs, some upgrades in the building
within itself. And a couple other
miscellaneous stuff. I'm already in
$430,000
besides what I purchased the actual
property for. I'm taking a big risk in
my business because I'm going to invest
into [music]
more educators. I'm investing into
traders to come into the trading floor
and trade. I'm taking a risk with the
actual trading itself because I need to
back [music] these traders that are
going to come to the trading floor, and
they need to take trades, and
potentially make money. [music] So,
everything that I'm doing to get to the
next level as a a person, [music] as a
mentor, as a an entrepreneur has some
type of risk. Now, I have thought about
[music] this for years, and I have done
every precaution that I possibly [music]
could have to minimize this risk. I have
specifically dedicated a section of my
day to this so it doesn't take away from
what I'm doing. I've budgeted and have
spoken to many different contractors so
I can have a very rough idea of what I
am going to actually invest into this. I
have spoke to many different educators
and many different mentors that I'm
going to have to be part of the trading
floor, and kind of have them already set
up. And I've already spoken to some
successful traders that I've been
watching their track records for the
last 2 years. So, when they are part of
the trading floor, I know that they have
experience and that they've done this
before. So, I've taken my steps to
minimize my risk. These are almost like
my confluences to enter this type of
investment, this type of move.
Regardless the fact, there could still
be a massive flop. I think about it
every single day. Maybe I'm taking a big
risk and it just doesn't work. But, I
will never be able to live without
knowing what would happen if I would
have taken that risk. If I would have
never taken that risk and made that
decision,
>> [music]
>> I would have I would not feel happy with
myself because I feel like I'd be
letting myself down. I've feel like I've
been given this amazing potential and if
I don't take that opportunity to take
that to the max, I feel like I'm letting
myself down in my potential. So, if it
flops, it flops. I learn something and
then we move on to the next thing. But,
I'm calculating that risk even though
it's outside of trading, minimizing my
amounts of exposure so I can be
successful and have the best odds of
succeeding. Everything in trading will
always somehow correlate to real life
things. And honestly, scared money makes
no money. A lot of people want to have
the cool stuff and they want to have the
fun and they want to be at the cool
places but not risk anything.
They want to make the most amount of
money without putting anything at risk.
And there's actually a lot of people out
there that envy successful people
because they can't accept taking the
risk. Some people are just not okay with
risking something. Some people are very
content with doing a task and making
money. It's a transaction and they're
very okay with that. But then they'll
hate for no reason because
whatever they worked for in that
transaction, they won't want to risk to
make more money. They'd rather risk
their time rather than risk their money.
Scared money makes no money. Look, for
For last month I spent 4.8
million dollars last month. Look look
look let me just show you guys right
here.
This is what I spent out of my checking
account. This is not a loan. This is not
a credit card. 4.8 million dollars is
what I spent last month. Now, there's a
mix of expenses, investments,
residual
expenses that I have, but the truth of
the matter is is that I invested 45% of
that.
It's sitting in the bank account is
going to do nothing. Now, I get it. It's
very easy for me to say in a position
where I am now. Oh, if I had access to
millions of dollars, I would also invest
my money how you do. Well, what are you
risking in order to make millions of
dollars?
Are you learning anything new?
Are you taking any risk with yourself to
learn a new skill set to make money? Are
you making any investments at all?
You're not going to make millions of
dollars if you don't make any
investments. Money's not going to fall
in your lap. The average millionaire has
seven sources of income. Can't just rely
on one source of income. You need to do
something to make more money.
And that's the ultimate key to scaling.
You need to risk something to make
something. It's really that simple. You
just need to calculate that risk as best
as you can. And I get it. A lot of
people will probably be like, oh, if I
was in your position Alex with millions
of dollars, I would also invest into
many different things in order to make
more money.
And I just say, well, why don't you do
it now? What are you risking right now?
Oh, I don't have any money to risk, so I
can't make millions of dollars. People
will always find an excuse as to why
they're not successful.
I'm like, well, I
didn't make millions of dollars from
thin air.
I
took a risk as well. I risked not seeing
my family for 2 and 1/2 years. I risked
not going to Christmas events. I missed
not going to birthdays. I my two little
cousins, I didn't see them get born.
There was a lot of things that I took a
risk and I missed out on because I
wanted to be successful.
In order for you to get to the next
level, you need to put something at
risk. I risked my
integrity. I I risked my
my morals by going up against all odds
that my family didn't believe in me. I
risked it all to get to the point where
I am now and I was not going to stop
until I did.
Now, some people aren't okay with
risking half of that. Well, if you
aren't okay with risking half of that,
then you can expect to have half of what
I have.
What you're willing to put at risk is
what you're going to get in return. And
it's not just about money. Money is just
a tool that is going to get you more of
that. But there's things at the
beginning that don't require money that
is a risk that will get you to that next
point. And some people just aren't
willing to do it. And that's totally
fine. But you can't expect to have the
same thing as someone that is willing to
risk it all every single time.
And some people even forget that I
worked at Dunkin' Donuts. Like that was
a reality in my life at one point. And I
get it. I've been successful for a very
long time, so a lot of people just meet
this version of me right now. But if we
were to go back to 2017, 2018, I would
literally be asking you what size coffee
do you want and what type of donut would
you want. I would have the cup ready in
my hand so I can serve the coffee.
And
it almost seems like that was so long
ago and it almost seems like that wasn't
a real part of my life, but it very much
was. And I understand what it takes to
get from that point to where it is now.
And [music] that's
being willing, able to sacrifice things
that other people aren't willing to
sacrifice.
>> [music]
>> So if I'm willing to sacrifice things
that other people aren't willing to
sacrifice, I'm going to have things that
[music] other people simply can't have.
And what gets me sometimes is that some
of you guys it's not even about the
money.
Some of you guys don't even want to risk
your own comfort.
Nonetheless, the money. I was 19 years
old.
Already being $30,000 in debt. I asked
my parents for money. I asked my aunt
for money. I risked my own money to
learn trading. You know how
uncomfortable those conversations were?
Having to ask my parents for an extra
$500 for whatever excuse I made at that
time, well, I'm putting it into the
market, losing it. You know how
uncomfortable it was to miss these
family events because I didn't want to
have to explain to people that yes, I'm
still working at Dunkin' Donuts. No, I
didn't go to college. No, I don't have a
degree and I don't have nothing going
for me. I'm just trying to figure out
how to make money online. You know how
uncomfortable it was to bump into my
family in places and have to explain
that. So, I took every possible risk
when I meet some of you guys in person,
you guys say, "Hey, yeah, I
can't watch your 10-hour tutorial video
because I get home tired from work."
Well, that is pretty pathetic because if
you aren't even willing to risk an hour
of your time to learn
education that can completely change
your journey, this just really isn't
meant for you. This is a journey that
will reward the strong. The weak will
not survive. If you aren't ready to put
up a fight, it's just better for you to
stay where you are. If you're not ready
to wake up every single day and fight,
just stay where you are. You're going to
save yourself money, you're going to
save yourself time and you won't have to
deal with the story that you never made
it. And when this individual told me
that they couldn't make time to watch a
10-hour YouTube video to learn how to
trade completely for free on YouTube,
that got to me because I put 20 to 25
hours of my time. I made time to make
that video. I put money into my team to
edit that video and I just put it out
there for you guys. And then someone
comes to me and tells me that they don't
have time to watch it.
I just told them, "Hey, it's better if
you just don't even ever watch it. It's
okay. You're not built for this. There's
just other roles for you that will make
more sense for you and will fit in
better with you. That's why 1% of people
will be successful. 99% want it, but
they won't do what you need to do in
order to get to it. And a lot of this
behavior is outside of trading, but I've
seen this behavior be
magnified as soon as these people get
involved into trading. I've seen many
traders, as soon as they enter a
position, self-sabotage. They enter a
position and then they automatically
start rethinking their decision as to
why they even entered that trade. As if
they did not do a pre-market analysis, a
top-down analysis as to why they should
be entering that trade. Soon as they
enter the trade, click the buy or sell
button, they're second-guessing
everything that they have just done
because the trade doesn't immediately go
into the profit where they entered the
trade. Now, that ends up sabotaging
traders because they might be onto
something good. They might have learned
a good strategy. They might actually
have an edge. But as soon as they enter
the position, because they don't have
immediate satisfaction, they're not
granted with that right that second,
they second-guess themselves. And
they're not patient. The market rewards
the patient, the people that end up
letting the market play out. Just
because you entered a position doesn't
mean the market has been waiting for you
for you to enter, so it goes directly
into that direction. The market moves in
waves. There's specific sessions that
will be stronger for certain pairs and
will be weaker for other pairs. And when
you enter a position in or out of those
sessions, it significantly affects how
your trade is going to play out. But
some people almost forget that as soon
as they enter a position. All they think
about at that point is just winning.
And they don't take into consideration
the actual art of losing. The beauty of
trading, and this is why I believe it is
the best business model online 2026 and
forever, is because
you can pre-calculate what you're going
to risk in the position.
And you can have a never-ending upside
potential. When you go into a position,
you know the most you're going to lose
where your stop loss is 100 bucks. You
will never lose more than $100.
Now, for some reason people enter a
trade and they start to second-guess
their position and get scared to lose.
Why are you scared to lose what you have
already pre-calculated that risk? Well,
what that leads me to tell is that
you were never okay with risking that
money in the first place. You never were
okay with having any risk exposed. You
just wanted to make money and not accept
the risk. And that's why traders will
fail because they get emotionally
attached to whatever money they're
putting into the account. Any other
business model out there, let's say you
want to open up a Amazon store, you need
to hire employees, you need to invest
into a website, you need to find a
product, stock up an inventory, invest
in ads. Look at all these different five
steps I just thought of in just 1
second. That is all
endless amounts of investment and no
guarantee that those products will sell
and you'll make that money back. There's
no fixed loss. There's continuous loss
that can continue to happen. Those
products can never sell and you lost
that money. And you might never even
make any money. With trading, you know
exactly how much you're going to lose
and you know exactly how much you're
going to gain. And you're going to get
that answer whether it's 30 minutes, an
hour, 4 hours, a day, a week, but you
are seeing it happen in real time. You
don't depend of other people. The market
is going to dictate that to you right
away. And for some reason, traders
reverse the roles right back to them. As
soon as they enter the position, they
think that they're influencing the
market in some type of way, and that's
why it should go straight to take
profit. And if it doesn't, and it goes
straight to stop loss, the market did
something wrong and not them. And them
putting the blame on the market is
already the first mistake that they're
doing because they're not taking
accountability for the type of trade.
They have just themselves clicked the
buy or the sell button. And that takes
me to my next point where trading takes
massive amount of commitment. It takes
commitment to your word, to yourself, to
your strategy, to your risk, to your It
just takes commitment all around. As
soon as you enter a position, you need
to commit to the trade. Whether it is a
big risk that you have taken or whether
it is a small risk that you have taken.
Whether you're around break even for 24
hours or whether it is going straight
into drawdown from the moment you enter
[music] it. You need to commit to that
position. Where you place your stop
loss, if you have a proper plan, the way
we do it, I place my stop loss at an
area where if it gets hit, I am entirely
wrong. If price is halfway through my
stop loss, I'm not just going to close
the position halfway through a loss so I
can say, "Oh, I only took half a loss."
That means that I'm completely
disregarding my analysis and the whole
reason why my stop loss is there. My
stop loss is there to stop me out where
if it gets hit, I am entirely wrong.
People close out at 70% into their stop
loss because they don't want to lose
that extra money. They want to save it.
Well, then that means your stop loss is
not strategically placed and you just
threw it on the chart for whatever
reason and you don't want to lose that
money that you have already risked.
That's a problem and you will never be
successful that way. Another problem
that people do and they're not having
proper commitment is when they enter a
position and it start going into profit.
As soon as the trade starts going into
some profit, let's say it goes halfway
into the profit, price starts having a
small retracement. What do traders do?
Automatically panic and close out on the
position 50% of their take profit
because they were scared that they were
going to miss out on profits.
That is a mistake as well. You should
not be closing your position before it
gets to your take profit. You need to
have that positive risk to reward to
make back the the
If I were to enter a position, for
example, and let's say I were to lose
$1.
Now, the next position is a winning
position. It goes halfway into my take
profit, and it looks like it's starting
to have a retracement, and I close out
at halfway of that trade. Guess what
ends up happening? I only make back half
of my loss. If I make back half of my
loss, I have a negative risk-to-reward
ratio. My risk-to-reward ratio needs to
be greater than what I lose. So, if I
risk $1, the minimum I need to gain at
all times is $2. So, whenever I take a
win, I make back the loss, and I'm in
profit. Traders have serious commitments
with letting the trade make it to the
take profit entirely. And I'm just going
to be straight up and blunt right now.
If you can't commit to your take profit,
you will never be successful. You can be
a great trader, you can be a great
top-down analysis, technical analysis,
have the best stop-loss, and if you
don't commit to your trade hitting your
take profit, you will never make enough
to make back for your losses and stay in
profit. You will have losses. Losses are
unavoidable in the markets.
But, if you don't have a positive
risk-to-reward, you're never going to
make enough to make back for those
losses and then give you the profit that
you are
purposely trading the market for. So,
the commitment that traders have, the
issue that commitment traders have is
letting that trade hit their take
profit, and them being scared that
they're going to leave money on the
table or miss out on profits. I can have
a trade be 99%
from my take profit, and I won't close
it out.
That is not the purpose of the trade.
The purpose of my trade is so it 100%
hits my take profit. Once price hits the
take profit, I will close out my
position entirely. I've had positions
make it 99%
into my take profit and go all the way
back down and hit my stop-loss. Now,
some people say, "Why don't you just go
to break even?" I I go to break even.
I don't believe in that.
Oh, why do you let a winning position
turn into a losing position? I was
already okay with risking that amount of
money in the first place. I've had many
positions in the past where they're 99%
from my take profit, come back to my
entry, take me out of break even when I
used to go to break even, and then fly
past my take profit to a 1:3, 1:4.
Because the problem is I was scared of
commitment. I was scared of the risk.
Now, that's what traders that go to
break even are. They're scared of
committing to the trade, and they're
scared of the risk that they had in the
first place. Has nothing to do with
turning a winning position into a losing
position. That is a stigma, that is a
narrative that traders have just
created. You need to commit to the
position. It either hits your take
profit or hits your stop loss. No in
between. And talking about losses, I
actually love this one.
You can still lose a position and still
be right. These are the famous wick
outs, liquidity grabs, ditties, fake
outs, market sweeps, liquidation,
whatever you want to call it. It's where
you end up having your stop loss placed
at an area where if it gets hit, you're
entirely wrong. And the market has a
flash move, gets there really fast, and
then goes straight into your take
profit. You were right about the
direction, but you got liquidated. You
got faked out, you got wicked out,
whatever you want to call it. That is
unavoidable.
That is part of the game. There is no
way that you can avoid one of these
situations happening. It is just
impossible. These are things that happen
in the market, and they're the cost of
trading. Best example is you can have a
your car just get washed from the car
wash, and you could be driving down the
road and a bird splats, shits right on
your windshield. It's part of having a
car. It's part of driving on the road.
If you don't want to get on, if you
don't want to have to clean that up
after, don't drive on the road or don't
have a car. If you don't want to be
exposed to wick outs, if you don't want
to be exposed to these fake outs, don't
take the trade in the first place. Just
don't trade at all.
But if you don't trade, then you won't
have the benefits of the reward that you
can take. It is unavoidable to avoid
these wick outs. I have attempted to
make my stop loss bigger. I've attempted
to wait for the wick outs or the fake
outs to happen. I've attempted to have a
indicator to let me know when it could
potentially happen. It is unpredictable.
You spend more time focusing on
something that can potentially never
even happening rather than focusing on
what is right in front of you. You can
spend more time driving on the road
looking up for birds, making sure that
none of them are going to on you,
rather than just focusing on the road
that is right in front of you. You
focusing on the bird, you can miss your
exit, you can take a red light and then
hit somebody else. You focusing on these
fake outs and these liquidity grabs, you
can miss out the opportunity that's
right in front of you and take the trade
that you shouldn't even be taking in the
first place. It is unavoidable and you
can still lose a trade that you are
correct about. All you have to do is
react and adapt and at that point, enter
a position that would make sense. So,
that is unavoidable. And honestly, I
wanted to leave my favorite points for
last because I think it's something that
people overlook and they're almost
scared of.
And that's letting the market show you
its hand first. Imagine if you were to
go play cards with someone and you are
able to see their cards first before you
even place a bet, before you even make a
decision, you get to see their cards and
then you get to see your cards and you
get to decide, you know what, I want to
play or you know I don't want to play.
That would give you a major advantage.
That would make your odds of succeeding
a lot higher, right? It's almost common
sense.
Well, it's the exact same thing.
For me, what I like to do in the market
is I like for the market to give me its
hand first. Even if I get a worse entry,
even if I get a lower entry, even if I
have to put a bigger stop loss, even if
I have to hold the trade for a little
bit longer.
I rather let the market show me its hand
first. I don't like taking a trade off
of loads of anticipation. Taking a trade
is already taking a massive
anticipation. You're anticipating it's
going to go in one direction versus the
other. That already within itself is
unpredictable. Why would you add more
steps to that unpredictability without
having any confirmation? I like to wait
for the market to show me its hand first
on the higher time frames. I like to
wait for weekly and daily rejections. If
I'm going to enter a trade at a daily
area of interest, for example,
why would I enter the trade on the first
hour rejection candlestick that I get?
No. I'd rather wait for the market to
give me a daily rejection. Confirm to me
that you're going to reject this daily
area and even have a little bit of a
push to the upside. Give me the
confirmation you're actually going in
that direction and all I have to do is
hop in that direction. I don't want to
predict the perfect bottom or the
perfect top. I want the market to give
me some indication that is actually
going in that direction. I don't want to
be the first guy to be at the concert.
No, I don't want to be the first guy
there. I'd rather see that there's a lot
of people going into the concert, that
it, you know, the artist is actually
going to show up. Okay, then I'll go. I
might not get the best seats, but at
least I'm not taking the extra step
where I'm the first guy there and I'm
waiting for hours for the artist to show
up. I might not get the best entry in
the market because I'm waiting for this
hand to be shown first, but at least I'm
getting a better confirmation and I'm
more comfortable with taking that risk.
That is has been my biggest edge in the
market because I am literally entering
with what the market is telling me. Now,
again, you have to know how to identify
that. You have to know on how to
properly wait for that and how to
properly scale in with that. But, with
whatever type of strategy that you have,
you know what your entry signal would
be, whatever it is.
Now, imagine entering an hour after that
confirmation has happened.
After your entry signal has happened,
you should have the market go in your
direction or go against it. Imagine you
can enter the trade an hour after your
entry signal.
If you were right, you might enter a
little bit higher, which you technically
miss out on some profits, or two, you
might avoid a loss entirely because if
the market is going against you,
you probably won't enter that trade at
all. Or let's say you did, you would
have a much better entry. So, letting
the market play off and letting it have
its hand first, letting it do what it's
supposed to do, will give you a major
advantage. And that is what I have been
doing for the last
2 years of my trading career, and that's
where I've been able to scale the most.
Been able to avoid the most amount of
losses, and I've been able to optimize
on wins because the market is showing me
it's going to be a winning trade. So, I
jump right in it. The market is showing
me it's going to be a losing trade, so I
decide to stay away or get a better
entry because it's coming back perfectly
into where it rejected it, for example.
This is a major advantage if you know
how to use it correctly. And I hope you
guys enjoyed this video. I know it's a
very different video than what I
normally do. I give you guys some
insights on my personal life, on some
things that have challenged me and have
really built character in my life, have
taught me a lot, and I've really learned
from it. And I really hope you guys can
take this information that I have to
share it with it and have immense
amounts of value. Even if you take one
of the lessons that I have just taught
in this video, it can completely change
everything. There's small quotes in my
life that I live by every single day,
and I hope to be one of those for you
guys in this video. Uh update on the
Bugatti. The Bugatti should be done
hopefully next month, month and a half.
We're waiting for the kit to come by.
Maybe you guys know who I am because of
the Bugatti series you've been following
it along. Maybe you have no idea who I
am. Well, just a guy on the internet
that trades, likes to have fun, and
crashed the Bugatti and is fixing it.
And hopefully we can fix it, take it up
to top speed again, and just
continuously have fun. So, hope you guys
enjoyed this video. Hope your 2026
continues to be extremely successful. If
you guys enjoyed this video and liked
it, make sure to hit it a like, thumbs
up. Make sure to subscribe down below.
Ladies and gentlemen, I will see you in
the next video. Take care, guys, and
I'll see you all.